<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Versiones</string>
    <string name="Beta">First version of Android released on the HTC G1. It included all the basic Google programs (search, mail, contacts, calendar, etc.) along with synchronization. In February 2009, Version 1.1 added the capability of saving attachments in messages.</string>
    <string name="Cupcake">Support for Widgets, such as a search box into the app on the home screen, virtual keyboards, MPEG-4 video and YouTube/Picasa uploading.</string>
    <string name="Donut">Search expanded to include bookmarks and history. More camera integration and features.</string>
    <string name="Eclair">Support for Microsoft Exchange mail. Search expanded to include SMS and MMS messages, and HTML5 support in the browser. More camera features, including flash, zoom and white balance.</string>
    <string name="Froyo">Support for Bluetooth hands free, push notifications, Wi-Fi hotspot functionality and greater screen resolution. Better Microsoft Exchange and Android Market integration.</string>
    <string name="Gingerbread">Introduced on the Samsung Galaxy Nexus S, support was added for VoIP, enhanced copy/paste, front-facing camera, AAC audio and near field communication (NFC). Gingerbread allowed for screens with WXGA and higher resolution.</string>
    <string name="Honeycomb">Introduced on the Motorola Xoom, Honeycomb was a tablet-only version that took advantage of larger screens. Touted as "3D Holographic," it added toolbars at top and bottom and incorporated tabbed browsing and other desktop features. When plugging into a computers USB port, Honeycomb used Microsofts Media Transfer Protocol (see MTP) for file transfer rather than connecting as a USB mass storage device.</string>
    <string name="IceCreamSandwich">Introduced on Samsungs Galaxy Nexus, Ice Cream Sandwich (ICS) combined Gingerbread and Honeycomb versions into one. ICS added a raft of new features, including facial recognition unlocking, resizable Widgets, Wi-Fi Direct and touchscreen keys in lieu of hardware Home, Menu and Back buttons. It also introduced NFC data transfer (see Android Beam).</string>
    <string name="JellyBean">Jelly Bean provided the user with information automatically throughout the day (see Google Now). Also included were improved camera features and notifications. An internal "Project Butter" made Android run a bit smoother, and the speech-to-text function (voice typing) worked without an Internet connection, although not quite as accurately. Jelly Bean also included an improved voice search, which is the counterpart to Apples Siri.</string>
    <string name="KitKat">A slicker, more polished interface and a host of changes, including improvements for instant messaging, photo editing and a full-screen display mode that was more immersive. Support for older phones with less than 1GB of RAM memory. "OK Google" was added to activate a voice search.</string>
    <string name="Lollipop">A redesigned user interface, known as Material Design, with notifications adhering to the card-based Google Now system. The Java Dalvik runtime engine was replaced by Android Runtime (ART), which provides cross-platform support for ARM, x86 and MIPS CPUs. Enterprise features included separating personal and business apps. Lollipop defaulted to encrypting the users data to prevent theft in the event the device was compromised. The users passcode was required to unlock the device and data. See Google Now.</string>
    <string name="Marshmallow">Major features were Android Pay mobile payment system and standardized fingerprint support, automatic data backup to the Google cloud, more context awareness of the user in Google Now and integration of the SD card into internal storage. Instead of agreeing to a slew of permissions before an app is installed, an app could be programmed to ask users for their consent when a resource is actually needed, such as contacts when emailing a photo. The Google Now voice search could be accessed from the lock screen, and Doze Mode sleeps the device after no activity for 30 minutes (notifications still come through). See Android Pay.</string>
    <string name="Nougat">If the app is compliant, it could be resized and moved around on screen as with a desktop computer. The Settings menu showed more information without going to a second level, a slider changed the display resolution and emergency info could be displayed on the lock screen. A Virtual Reality mode supported Googles upcoming Daydream VR feature, and Doze mode helped with battery life. An internal architecture created two stages: one that Google provided across all devices, and a second stage for vendor-supplied software. In addition, OpenJDK, the official Java open source runtime version, replaced Apache Harmony.</string>
    <string name="Oreo">Version 8 improves battery life and performance by limiting what apps can do in the background. Users have more control over notifications and autofill, as well as support for high-quality Bluetooth codecs (see LDAC) and nearby Wi-Fi awareness (see Wi-Fi Aware).</string>
    <string name="Pie">Version 9 provides numerous enhancements. It improves battery life by offering adaptive features such as learning how you use apps and change brightness. Pie also predicts what you might do next. Slices display relevant parts of apps, and gestures can be used in addition to buttons. Multiple and external cameras are supported, and apps for work can be visually separated. Up to five Bluetooth devices can be connected, and incoming calls can be sent to all of them with different volume levels.In 2018, Samsung introduced a new user interface for Galaxy S and Note devices running Pie. See One UI.</string>
    <string name="Android10">No more sweet tooth naming, the 10th version of Android is number 10. Like Facebook Messengers Chat Heads, round Bubbles icons overlay on the screen when someone is phoning, and Bubbles can be employed by third-party app developers. Connecting to a Wi-Fi network is easier by scanning the QR code on your friends phone, and vice versa. There is more user control over location information, privacy permissions and notifications. Project Mainline pushes security updates on phones that originally ship with Android 10. Parental permissions have been enhanced.</string>
</resources>
